Finding Aid for the George Marion O’Donnell Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Series VI: Collected writings/publications
  - Poetry, various authors, nd, 1940, 1949, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Porter, Katherine Anne, “Noon Wine,” Story, June 1937 (Box 5)
  - Saturday Review of Literature, 19 March 1949 (Box 5)
  - Stewart, Randall, “On the Meaning of Vanderbilt,”, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Stormy Petrel (Oglethorpe University), 24 February 1960 (Box 5)
  - Sutcliffe, Denham, “W-S-Ow-R-W,”, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Tate, Allen -- two poems, typescript, nd (Box 5)
  - Thomas, Richard A., “Amiel’s Portrait of a Poet,”, 1936 (Box 5)
  - Time, 8 August 1955 (Box 5)
  - Yale News, 23 April 1958 (Box 5)
- Series VII: Clippings
  - Clippings, c. 1940s-50s (2f) (Box 6)
- Series VIII: Miscellany
  - Miscellany (Box 6)
  - Miscellany -- Address book (Box 6)
  - Miscellany -- Creative and performing arts memorabilia (Box 6)
  - Miscellany -- Recordings (3 albums) (Box 6)
    - Allen Tate reading his poems “The Mediterranean” and “The Cross,”, 1937 (Box 6)
    - George M. O’Donnell reading “That Day” and “Her Distress,” (Box 6)
    - George M. O’Donnell reading “Mask of Christ” and “Descent of Leaf,”, 1941 (Box 6)
- Series IX: Photographs
  - O’Donnell, George M., c. 1914-20, 1929, 1937, 1940, 1947, 1950, 1960-61 (21 items) (Box 6)
  - Family, c. 1870s-1920s (10 album pages, 45 loose photographs (Box 6)
  - Family -- Tintypes -- c. 1860s-70s (7 items total; 3 are painted) (Box 6)
  - from: Puritan Village, by Sumner C. Powell, nd (Box 6)
- Series X: Gordon Roysce Smith, Jr.
  - Biographical and personal, 1944, 1962-63 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: (Box 6)
  - Alabama Polytechnic Institute (Auburn), 1942 (Box 6)
  - Ames, Elizabeth, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Atlanta Graphic Arts Center, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Barton, Craig, 1964, 1966-67 (4) (Box 6)
  - Berg, Norman, 1957, 1960 (2) (Box 6)
  - Bewley, Marcus, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Brown, Wendell and Eve, 1957, 1960, 1962-64 (6) (Box 6)
  - Butler, John, nd, 1944, 1947 (3) (Box 6)
  - Censorship, Georgia, 1953 (5 rec’d and 3 sent, plus 17 other items) (Box 6)
  - Cerf, Bennett, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Chaney, Bev, Jr., nd (Box 6)
  - Cohen, Barbara, 1954, 1957-58 (5) (Box 6)
  - Cooper, Marie, nd, 1947-48 (4) (Box 6)
  - Cox, Chap, nd (Box 6)
  - Crane, Vernon, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Crosby, Caresse, 1947, 1949 (2 rec’d and 1 sent) (Box 6)
  - Crosby, Midlred, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Davidson, Martha, 1957 (Box 6)
  - DeBoer, Bernhard, 1951-52, 1954 (5) (Box 6)
  - Dempsey, John, 1969 (Box 6)
  - East, Charles, 1963, 1971 (2) (Box 6)
  - Emory University Alumni Association, 1942 (2) (Box 6)
  - Falck-Baranan, Marianne, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Fry, Beatrice, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Funeral arrangements, George M. O’Donnell, 1962 (2) (Box 6)
  - Fryxell, Lucy, 1944 (Box 6)
  - Greenberg, Clem, 1947-50, 1952, 1954, 1960, 1962, 1967 (Box 6)
  - (32 rec’d and 2 sent) (Box 6)
  - Haffenden, John, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Halpern, Maizie, 1954, 1956-57 (5) (Box 6)
  - Hays, Marguerite, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Herrington, Lillian N., 1962 (Box 6)
  - Box 6 (cont’d): Series X -- Gordon Roysce Smith, Jr. (cont’d) (Box 6)
  - Correspondence (cont’d): (Box 6)
  - Hobart, Alice Tisdale, 1944 (Box 6)
  - Hoepfner, Ted, 1944-45 (4) (Box 6)
  - Hoyleman, Merle, 1950, 1962-65, 1976 (9) (Box 6)
  - Jones, Ibbie, 1944-47 (14) (Box 6)
  - Kappa Sigma, 1944-45 (2) (Box 6)
  - Kirby, T.A., 1949 (Box 6)
  - Koch, Frederick, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Lawrence, Seymour, 1961-62 (2) (Box 6)
  - Leatherman, LeRoy, nd (Box 6)
  - Levin, Hilda Cohen, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Logan Middie, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Lowe, Harry, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Lyons, Rebie, 1962 (Box 6)
  - McDonough, Richard P., 1977 (Box 6)
  - McDowell, David, 1950 (Box 6)
  - McGehee, Edward, 1945, 1947-48 (6) (Box 6)
  - McLellan, Pearl, 1949, 1962-63 (6) (Box 6)
  - Montesi, Al, 1962 (2) (Box 6)
  - Morgan, Elliott, 1947, 1949, 1959, 1963-64 (5) (Box 6)
  - National Association of College Stores, 1958-59 (6) (Box 6)
  - National Association of College Stores, 1965 (19 rec’d and 7 sent) (Box 6)
  - O’Donnell, George Marion, nd, 1944-45 (173) (4f) (Box 6)
  - Correspondence (cont’d): (Box 7)
  - Packer, Herbert, 1946, 1951, 1954 (14) (Box 7)
  - Palmer, Harriet Smith, 1946-47, 1962 (4) (Box 7)
  - Paroissien, H.F., nd, 1951-57, 1960 (15) (Box 7)
  - Phillips, A., 1945 (Box 7)
  - Pollock, Charles, nd (Box 7)
  - Posters (3f) (Box 7)
    - nd, 1967-68 (3) (Box 7)
    - Invoices, 1967-68 (Box 7)
    - Brochures, Catalogues, 1967-68 (Box 7)
  - Publisher’s Weekly, 1956 (1 sent) (Box 7)
  - Rawls, June, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Scotland (Book trade), 1970 (3 rec’d and 19 enclosures) (Box 7)
  - Shinn, John, nd, 1944-45 (3) (Box 7)
  - Correspondence (cont’d): (Box 7)
  - Smith, Dr. and Mrs. Gordon R., 1944-49, 1959-62 (12 rec’d and 1 sent) (Box 7)
  - Smith, Mildred C., 1953 (2) (Box 7)
  - Smith, Roger, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Sarah T., 1944 (Box 7)
  - Sorum, R.E., 1946-48, 1952, 1957, 1959 (10) (Box 7)
  - Strand, Mark, nd, 1964 (6) (Box 7)
  - Sullivan, Mrs., 1962 (Box 7)
  - Sutcliffe, Priscilla, 1946-49, 1952, 1964 (9 rec’d and 1 sent) (Box 7)
  - The Tiger’s Eye, 1948 (3) (Box 7)
  - Topp, Mildred, 1950, 1962 (5) (Box 7)
  - Tucker, Carol, 1957 (Box 7)
  - Turner E. Smith & Co., 1949 (Box 7)
  - Tyre, Nedra, 1954 (3) (Box 7)
  - Washington University, St. Louis, 1971 (2) (Box 7)
  - Weber, Olga S., 1962 (Box 7)
  - Wildman, John, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Williams, Mrs. T.H., 1945 (2) (Box 7)
  - Willison, John, 1962-63 (4) (Box 7)
  - Willoughby, C.L., nd (Box 7)
  - Witzel, Edward J., 1956 (Box 7)
  - Woodbury, Lee, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Yerkes, Bill, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Zalewski, Steve, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Sender not identified, nd, 1945, 1957, 1960, 1962-63, 1971 (11) (Box 7)
  - Greeting cards, announcements, invitations, 1944, 1958, 1962, 1965, nd (37 items) (Box 7)
  - Writings, Published or Presented (Box 7)
    - “Being Arbitrary: The Opinionated Man,”, 1970 (Box 7)
    - “Dupes for Whom?” National Association of College Stores, 1959 (Box 7)
    - “Paperbackground,” National Association of College Stores, 1959 (Box 7)
    - Poetry, 1948-49, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Writings, Unpublished (Box 7)
    - Poetry, nd (Box 7)
    - Prose, nd (Box 7)
  - Drawings, nd (3f) (Box 7)
  - Calendars, 1962-63, 1965-66, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Notes, Miscellaneous, nd (Box 7)
  - Collected writings/publications (Box 7)
    - Banks, J. Richard, various poems, nd (Box 7)
    - Dembo, L.S, “Norman Holmes Pearson on H.D.: An Interview,” (Box 7)
    - Contemporary Literature Autumn, 1969 (Box 7)
    - The Faulkner Newsletter, 1981-82 (8 issues) (Box 7)
    - Hoyleman, Merle, Letters from Christopher, excerpts, nd (Box 7)
    - Nash, Ogden, “The Seven Spiritual Ages of Mrs. Marmaduke (Box 7)
    - Moore,” copied and illustrated by G. Roysce Smith, Jr. (Box 7)
    - Shavzin, Alan, “A Day at the Zoo,”, 1959 (Box 7)
    - Sutcliffe, Priscilla, “Bobby Birthdaybird’s Trip,”, nd (Box 7)
    - Yale News, 26 May 1960 (Box 7)
  - Clippings, 1960s (Box 7)
  - Clippings -- Censorship in Georgia, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Miscellany, nd (Box 7)
  - Photographs -- pictures of Smith, pictures of booksellers conventions, 1 8x10 of Charles M. Schulz signing books and 1 4×5 negative of Cleanth Brooks signing books (68 items total) (Box 7)
- Series XI: Oversize
  - George Marion O’Donnell (Box 7)
  - Miscellany -- Poster announcing GMOD reading from his own work, 4/17/46, Harvard University (Box 7)
  - Photographs (Box 7)
    - Unidentified -- one white man, two white women, and one African-American woman, c. 1860s or 1870s (Box 7)
    - “The Big Four,” -- two men and women, c. 1910s (Box 7)
    - “A bedroom at Stronghold, Greenwood, Mississippi,” (Box 7)
  - photograph by John Butler, 12 December 1948 (Box 7)
    - “Pearl McLellan, mistress of Stronghold.. .” (Box 7)
      - 12 December 1948; photograph by John Butler (Box 7)
    - “Stronghold, Greenwood, Mississippi, 12 December 1948 (Box 7)
      - Built in 1847. Architecture, Greek revival.” (Box 7)
      - Photograph by John Butler. (Box 7)
    - Albums (7 total) (Box 7)
      - c. 1890s-1920s, [family ?], (2 albums) (Box 7)
      - Red cover, GMOD and friends, 1930s (Box 7)
      - Green cover, GMOD and friends, 1934-37 (Box 7)
      - Blue cover, GMOD and friends, 1938-39 (Box 7)
      - Blue scrapbook, mostly clippings, entitled “Phenomena in the Arts,”, c. 1930s (Box 7)
  - Gordon Roysce Smith, Jr. (Box 7)
  - Two sketch books (Box 7)
  - Collected writings/publications: Life: John F. Kennedy Memorial Edition, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Miscellany (Box 7)
    - Certificate naming Smith to Connecticut’s “Standards of Decency” commission (Box 7)
    - Sketch by Bill Moulan (Box 7)
    - Movie posters (Box 7)
    - “Badman’s Gold”, (1951) (Box 7)
    - “Blazing Six Shooters”, (nd) (Box 7)
    - “Bury the Living”, (1957) (Box 7)
    - “The Disorderly Orderly”, (1964) (Box 7)
    - “East of Eden,” six different posters, (1955) (Box 7)
    - “Godzilla vs. The Thing”, (1964) (Box 7)
    - “Hercules”, (1959) (Box 7)
    - “Nightmare”, (1956) (Box 7)
    - “The Sniper”, (1952) (Box 7)
    - “The Women of Pitcairn Island”, (1956) (Box 7)